<?xml version='1.0' ?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
   "http://developer.arsdigita.com/docbook/dtd/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" >

<book>
<title>Directory Package Documentation</title>

<authorblurb>
<para>By <ulink url="mailto:mikeb@arsdigita.com">Mike Bonnet</ulink></para>
</authorblurb>

<abstract>
<title>Installation</title>
<para>
This is the Directory Package.  It is a very simple (1 page) package for listing 
and searching through the members of a subsite.  It is fully subsite-aware, using the 
<computeroutput>application_groups</computeroutput> functionality in ACS4.2 to define subsite membership.
</para>
<para>
If you're reading this, then you probably have the package installed already.  If not, 
load the .apm file into the package manager (/acs-admin/apm/) and click install.  The data
model for this package is very minimal (3 views) and should load very quickly.  If there are
any errors loading this package, make sure you are using ACS4.2, since this package requires 
the new subsite-scoping features.  If you geta "query returned no rows" error, visit the admin/groups 
page for your subsite, so that it can configure itself as necessary, and then try the Directory 
package again.
</para>
</abstract>

<abstract>
<title>Using the Directory Package</title>
<para>
Now that you have the package installed, you need to mount it somewhere.  If you only 
have one instance of the acs-subsite package mounted (the "Main Site") you can mount it anywhere 
under that package.  If you have multiple instances of acs-subsite, you can mount an instance of 
Directory under each subsite.
</para>
<para>
When listing users, the Directory package will find the nearest subsite above it on the site_nodes 
tree.  It will then list everybody that is a member of that subsite (based on membership in the 
<computeroutput>application_group</computeroutput> associated with that subsite, see 
packages/acs-subsite/sql/application-groups-create.sql).
</para>
<para>
A user can make themself a member of a subsite instance by visiting &lt;subsite_url&gt;/register/user-join.  
They will then show up in the Directory listing for that subsite.  An admin can also make a user a member of 
a subsite instance by going to &lt;subsite_url&gt;/admin/groups/?view_by=rel_type.  Note that to add a user to 
a subsite, they must be a member of all of the subsites above it in the site_nodes tree.  register/user-join takes 
care of this automatically, but an admin must manually handle all of the constraints when adding a new member.
</para>
<para>
The list of users displayed can be restricted by the letter their last name starts with, or a search criteria.  
The search shows users that have the search criteria anywhere in their first name, last name, or email address 
(case-insensitive).  When searching, a "browse by letter" link will appear next to the search box, to allow you to 
go back to browse mode.  When searching or browsing, the number of results per page can be restricted by clicking 
one of the "show" links on the left side.  You also have the choice of viewing "subsite members" (people who have 
been explicitly made a member of the current subsite) or "all users" (all registered users of the site).
</para>
</abstract>

</book>

